Haiqing (Connie) Kang

Flushing, NY 11358 | U.S. Permanent Resident | 814-441-6329 | hgk1121@gmail.com | Github | LinkedIn | Portfolio

Software Engineer

Full stack developer experienced in Ruby on Rails, Python and JavaScript based programming with a background in healthcare data analytics and a solid understanding of data structure and algorithm. With 3 years of analytics experience and 1 year of leadership experience, I bring strong problem solving skills, both technically and non-technically.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript | React.js | Redux | Ruby | Ruby on Rails | Python | Django | CSS | HTML | SQL | Git | Tableau | Power BI

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

OneHealth - Github | Live

Web app where patients can schedule appointment with doctors based on availability, and rate and pay after the visits

- Built Rails API backend with two user models and user data populated with Faker Gem
- Utilized Redux with React for efficient and organized state management
- Incorporated react library react-big-calendar and Moment Gem for visualized appointment scheduling
- Created text animation and interactive user interface using custom CSS and Material UI

TAB-TAB - Github | Live | Demo

Web app that allows users to track and split bills with other users

- Developed RESTful API endpoints for users, tabs and items using Ruby on Rails
- Realized secured backend user authentication using bcrypt
- Implemented user interface employing React, HTML, CSS (both custom and Ant Design), and react libraries such as animate.css and particle-bg

Fancy Photography - Github | Demo

React app that allows photographers to showcase and manage their work while visitors can interact with photographers

- Implemented a multi-page application using React, Bootstrap, HTML/CSS for state management and modern styling
- Incorporated json-server to store photographer work data and comments data, and create API CRUD actions
- Leveraged EmailJS to achieve sending emails to any smtp server from JavaScript

EXPERIENCE

Fidelis Care New York, NY Manager, Valued-Based Payment Data Analytics 09/2020 - 08/2021

- Managed the database for over 50 VBP partners, who oversee more than 34,000 providers and manage the care of over 900,000 Medicaid lives, with the goals to reduce cost and improve overall quality of care
- Collaborated cross-functionally with IT team and third-party analytics vendors to provide project requirements, resolve data issue, identify opportunities for report automation and database improvement
- Identified and developed meaningful data strategies through effective communication with stakeholders
- Spearheaded a team of 4 data analysts to effectively manage the data need for 53 VBP partners

Chinese Community Accountable Care Organization

New York, NY

Data Analyst, Team Lead

07/2018 - 09/2020

- Developed and maintained physician-facing population health dashboard from multiple data sources using Power BI to help practices better understand their patients
- Cleaned, compiled, and analyzed large claim data for more than 10,000 Medicare lives using Microsoft SQL Server, Python and Microsoft Excel
- Built the data infrastructure from the ground up and gathered and created documentations for educational purposes

EDUCATION

Flatiron School New York, NY Full Stack Web Development 09/2021 - 01/2022

New York University New York, NY

Master of Arts in Quantitative Economics and Econometrics (GPA: 3.76/4.00) 05/2018

Pennsylvania State University State College, PA Bachelor of Arts in Economics (GPA: 3.62/4.00) 05/2016